# Oralia Rivera Vicente

Computer Systems Engineer - Front-end Developer

Veracruz, México · linkedin.com/in/oralia-rivera-vicente · +52 922 125 23 23 · oralia.rivera.isc@gmail.com

I've been doing front-end development for about 3 years, creating intuitive and attractive user interfaces. I've experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript and frameworks such as VueJS, ReactJS and NextJS. Tested backend code with JUnit and Mockito and used Git with the Git Flow methodology on platforms such as GitHub and Gitlab.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IDS Comercial Benito Juarez, CDMX

Front-End Developer (Remote)

January 2023-April 2024

- Made improvements to the user interfaces of the insurance contracting process in a project for the banking sector using Jade and Angular 11.
- Managed and maintained the team website on Google Sites, ensuring updated and accessible information.
- Developed improvements to an airline's web application, using ReactJS, NextJS, JavaScript and CSS with Tailwind.
- Performed code analysis and created flowcharts in Figma.
- Connected and consumed internal APIs to reflect flight information on the front-end, ensuring accuracy.
- Investigated and updated dependencies in an Afores project to improve performance and eliminate vulnerabilities.
- Developed and executed unit tests using Junit and Mockito to ensure code quality.

Zenda.la CDMX

Front-End Developer (Remote)

November 2021–December 2022

- Migrated JavaScript code to TypeScript to improve code robustness and maintainability.
- Developed and implemented new components and features with ReactJS and TypeScript based on Figma designs.
- I implemented application internationalization using i18n to support multiple languages.
- I connected and consumed internal and external APIs to access data and map information on the frontend.
- I created landing pages for the company's allies using NextJS and TypeScript.

UNINDETEC Antón Lizardo, Veracruz

Front-End Developer Jr (On-site)

February 2021–July 2021

- I carried out the analysis and specification of the requirements for the development of the application.
- Designed user interfaces using Figma.
- Programmed the user interfaces with VueJS, JavaScript and CSS with Bootstrap.
- Implemented HTTP requests with Axios to send and receive data from internal APIs.
- Created validation rules for the app forms using Vuelidate and regular expressions.

Freelance Minatitlán, Veracruz

Front-End Developer (On-site)

February 2020-January 2021

• I developed websites using HTML, CSS and JavaScript for private companies.

# **EDUCATION**

# Instituto Tecnológico De Minatitlán

Minatitlán, Veracruz

Computer System Engineer Bachelor.

October 2021

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Scrum Developer by **CertiProf** January 2023.
- Scrum Fundamentals by **SCRUMstudy** January 2023.
- National Language Level Certification (CENNI), SEP September 2022.
- Scrum Fundamentals by Sprint Ágil October 2021.

### ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Autodidact.
- Creative.
- Teamwork.
- Leadership.
- Collaborative.
- Adaptability.
- Problem-Solving.

# **LANGUAGES**

- Spanish Naitve
- English B1